JAMIE SHERRIFF

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am working full time in the software industry as a software engineer after completing a Bachelor of Science Degree with a double major in Computer Science and Geography from the University of Canterbury. During my time at university I worked part time as an Intern QA engineer. Previously as a qualified electrical technician, I worked in the electronics industry for two years holding positions of production technician and team leader.

PERSONAL SKILLS AND ATTRIBUTES

- Able to work successfully as a member of a team.
- Ability to stay focused and reliable in a high pressure time constrained environment.
- Patient and a willingness to listen and learn.
- Determination to get the job done with a focus on quality.
- Always maintained a highly punctual and organised ethic throughout work and education.
- Good academic record with excellence awards in electronics.
- Acquired valuable people skills while working with a wide range of peers at work and during my education.
- Able to strive and achieve goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- Experienced using programming languages Python, Java, C, C# and web languages including PHP, JavaScript (frontend JS and backend with Node.JS) and databases with SQL.
- Development skills including Angular JS, native Android and the multiplatform mobile framework Appelerator titanium. Node.JS experience with packages including express, lodash, grunt and moment.
- Knowledgeable of Automation tools Selenium, Appium, Xcode Instruments, Android UI Automator and continuous integration software TeamCity and Jenkins.
- Understanding of test suites and applications using Microsoft's .Net framework with Visual Studio
- Developed and tested RESTful web services with Node.JS, Python and .Net
- Familiar with version control systems Mercurial, Git.
- Confident using test frameworks Mocha, pytest and load testing tools Locust and Jmeter.
- Skilled with the use of computers and electronic equipment. Computer systems experience covers Microsoft, Linux, OSX, iOS and Android.
- Proficient using ESRI's Arc GIS and have used QGIS.
- Capable of using spatial analysis software GeoDA, CrimeStat, PySAL and Exelis's ENVI for imagery.
- Have built many computer hardware systems and often install operating systems, patches, applications, firewalls and home networks.
- Have my own electronic workbench setup at home for conducting computing and electronic repair work.
 I also run my own web server and network at home.
- Found online at: https://github.com/jamie-sherriff and https://github.com/jamie-sherriff and https://github.com/jamie-sherriff and https://github.com/jamie-sherriff and https://bitbucket.org/jamiesherriff and https://bit

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2018 - Current: Senior Test Analyst at Ryman Healthcare

- Created the foundation of a Microsoft UWP application automation framework.
- Implemented new test management strategies.
- Designed, developed, executed and documented appropriate test strategies to verify high quality software.

2015 – 2018: Test Automation Engineer at Telogis A Verizon Company

- Designed and developed custom automation test frameworks for mobile and web applications.
- Development responsibilities including feature planning, bug fixing, performance analysis and improvements, build management and scrum participation.
- Improved test reporting to peers and managers while training developers and QA engineers to use and maintain established automation suites.
- Maintained existing and implemented new continuous integration infrastructure.
- Vehicle diagnostic hardware development and maintenance.

2014 – 2015: Junior Test Automation Engineer at Telogis.

- Involved in the design, architecting, developing and running of software automation systems and tools to ensure a high quality of software was met.
- Led the testing of new products and establishment of test suites.

2012 – 2014: Intern QA engineer at Telogis

- Test planning and execution, test progress reporting, improvement of testing processes and test environment and maintenance.
- Helped Implement mobile automation frameworks and established a UI automation test suites for company mobile applications on Android and test frameworks for mobile REST web services.

2011 – 2012: Production Technician and Team Leader at Enatel

• Led a team to produce electrical systems which included staff management, quality control, software testing, creating testing standards and liaising with engineers and management.

2010 - 2011: Test Technician at Enatel

 Tested power supply systems while being required to meet tight time deadlines and maintain high quality testing procedures. I was also trained to carry out quality assurance on products before shipping.

QUALIFICATIONS

2014:

• "Rapid Software Testing" course with testing professional James Bach.

2012-2014: University of Canterbury

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Geography with a B+ grade average over the duration of my degree. Maintained an A Grade average in my last year of study.
- My Geography major was focused on GIS courses and gained experience with commercial GIS software.
 This also included environmental processes and gained knowledge of geospatial and geographic analysis.
- Computer Science covered programming, software engineering, databases, networking, Internet technology, computer and operating systems, human interaction with software, and web architecture.

2009: Electec College of Technology

 Achieved the Electec College Certificate in Applied Electronics Technology with Distinction. Also achieved EST-A (Electrical Service Technician) qualification with a passmark of 95% and received a Top Achiever certificate from the EWRB.

2004–2008: Riccarton High School, Christchurch

Achieved NCEA level 3 with Excellence awards for level 3 Geography and Electronics.

INTERESTS

- IEEE member since 2012
- Enjoy running, biking and photography.
- Interested in computing, multimedia and electronics, and am always looking at new technology and its application to real world problems.
- Appreciate a good days fishing, hunting and four wheel driving.